{
    "id": "d4ff3aa176fe4e19a5fe633c6caeb913",
    "title": "Conditional Clauses Quiz",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "bf5e055dd4b044ed97680c2e85bec79a",
            "title": "Conditional Clauses Quiz",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "If you had invited her, she ...................................... with us.",
                    "description": "When the verb in the if-clause is in the past perfect tense, we use would / could have + past participle in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "could go",
                        "can go",
                        "could have gone"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "If I .......................... the opportunity, I would have gone to university.",
                    "description": "In the third conditional, we need a past participle in the if-clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "had",
                        "had had",
                        "will have"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "If I ............................. her number, I would call her.",
                    "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "know",
                        "knew",
                        "had known"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you take this medication, you ................................. well.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will get",
                        "would get",
                        "would have got"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you had sold your home then, you .............................. rich now.",
                    "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "will be",
                        "would be",
                        "would have been"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you ate your breakfast, you ................................ not be hungry now.",
                    "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "will",
                        "would",
                        "had"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you ............................ me, we both would have been happy.",
                    "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. \r\n",
                    "answers": [
                        "marry",
                        "married",
                        "had married"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you spoke a foreign language, you ............................... a better job.",
                    "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "could get",
                        "can get",
                        "could have got"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I could marry her if I ............................ to.",
                    "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "want",
                        "wanted",
                        "had wanted"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "If your computer ........................... you will lose unsaved work.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "crashes",
                        "crashed",
                        "had crashed"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If I am late, my father .......................... me to school.",
                    "description": "In the zero conditional, we use a simple present tense in both clauses.",
                    "answers": [
                        "takes",
                        "will take",
                        "would take"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you behaved more politely, they .............................. help you.",
                    "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/ could/ might + infinitive in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "may help",
                        "might help",
                        "might have helped"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}